<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mercurial on (map solve problems)</title>
    <link>http://yantonov.com/categories/mercurial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mercurial on (map solve problems)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:54:21 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/mercurial/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye mercurial</title>
      <link>http://yantonov.com/blog/2016/03/12/bye-bye-mercurial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:54:21 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yantonov.com/blog/2016/03/12/bye-bye-mercurial/</guid>
      <description>Has just migrated all my mercurial repositories to git. Its a little bit sad, but it will increase uniformity. More over there is gitlab which provides free private repositories as well as bitbucket.
P.s. here is a simple script aimed to convert hg repo to git,
maybe it will be helpful</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export files changed at revision from mercurial</title>
      <link>http://yantonov.com/blog/2014/12/07/export-files-changed-at-revision-from-mercurial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 22:59:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yantonov.com/blog/2014/12/07/export-files-changed-at-revision-from-mercurial/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes (more precisely - rarely) you need to export files changed at given revision as directory tree instead of patch file.
Mercurial vcs has archive command which let you to export selected files at given revision:
hg archive --type files --rev $REVISION -I list_of_files  To list files changed at revision:
hg log -r $REVISION --template &#39;{files}\n&#39; | sed &#39;s/\n / -I /g&#39;  Here end of line character is used to handle the case of using space character in filename.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmable completion for git and mercurial</title>
      <link>http://yantonov.com/blog/2014/11/09/programmable-completion-for-git-and-mercurial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 22:52:36 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yantonov.com/blog/2014/11/09/programmable-completion-for-git-and-mercurial/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago i read excellent post about emacs library pcomplete.
The author described implementation of completion for git, mercurial version control system using this library. Article is really usefull, i used code as is, its easy and provides all you need, but later i have some problem with it.
First problem - eager evaluation. General commands for git and mercurial are calculated once. Great, there is no reason to call external process like git or hg multiple times but precalculation occured at script evaluation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
